So we're going to make a call to GPT four.
GPT 4에 전화를 걸 거예요
Oh, that's going to ask it to look through a set of links, figure out which ones are relevant, and
링크 세트를 검토하라고 요청하는군요 어떤 게 관련 있는지 알아내고
then replace them with fully qualified links.
완전히 자격 있는 링크로 대체하라고요
Um, and it's going to be a great, a great way of using llms because it requires particularly for selecting
llm을 사용하는 아주 좋은 방법이 될 겁니다 특히 관련 있는 링크를 선택해야
which links are relevant.
하니까요
It needs a sort of nuanced reasoning process.
추론 과정이 필요해요
Uh, so we're going to we're going to not only are we going to to use GPT four for this purpose, we're
이 목적으로 GPT 4를 사용할 뿐 아니라 JSON 형식으로 응답하도록
going to ask it to respond in the form of JSON in a way that specifies exactly the information that
요청할 겁니다 우리가 돌려받아야 할 정보를 정확히 지정하는 방식으로요
Now, later on, we're going to cover a technique called structured outputs, which is when we require
나중에 구조화 출력이라는 테크닉을 다루겠습니다 LLM이 아주 구체적인
the LLM to respond with a very specific format.
포맷으로 반응하도록 요구하는 경우죠
We effectively we specify the format that it needs to respond in.
응답해야 할 포맷을 지정하는 거죠
We're not going to do this today.
오늘은 안 돼요
We're just going to simply ask for JSON back.
JSON을 요청하는 거죠
And we're going to tell it the format that it needs to use to reply.
회신을 위해 사용해야 하는 포맷을 알려드리죠
And it's going to be great.
멋질 거예요
Uh, this works well for simple requests like this.
이렇게 간단한 요청에는 잘 통하죠
When you get more sophisticated, you you might need to use structured outputs.
IQ가 높아지면 구조적인 출력 작업을 해야 해요 IQ, IQ
And in week eight, when we build our Agentic AI framework, we're going to do just that.
8주 차에 에이전틱 인공지능 프레임워크를 만들 때 그걸 할 거예요
But for now, this is what we do.
하지만 지금은 이게 우리 일이에요
So we're going to to create a system prompt.
시스템 프롬프트를 생성할게요
The system prompt is where, of course we describe the task at hand and how it's to go about doing it.
시스템 프롬프트에는 당면한 작업과 그 작업 방법을 설명하는 글이 있죠
That is where we will be supplying this information.
거기서 정보를 제공할 거예요
Here's the system prompt.
시스템 프롬프트예요
You are provided with a list of links found on a web page.
웹페이지에 있는 링크 목록을 제공하죠
You are able to decide which of these links will be most relevant to include in a brochure about the
어떤 링크가 회사 브로슈어에 포함될지 결정할 수 있습니다
company, such as links to an about page or a company page, or a careers jobs page.
회사 페이지나 회사 페이지 직업 페이지 링크 같은 거요
You should respond in JSON as in this example.
이 예제처럼 JSON에서 응답해야 해요
And then there is an example passed in.
그리고 예시가 전달되죠
And when I said we're working with one shot prompting, that's really what I meant by giving it a specific
원 샷 프롬프트라고 한 건 특정 예제를 준다는 게 정말 그 뜻이었습니다
example that it could use with an about page and a careers page, and the way that we're specifying
어바웃 페이지나 직업 페이지와 함께 사용할 수 있도록요 그 형식을 지정하는 방법은 단순히
the format is simply by giving it an example you can see we're asking for a dictionary.
예제를 주는 겁니다 사전에 대해 묻는 걸 보실 수 있죠
It will have a single attribute links.
단일 특성 링크를 갖게 되죠
And that links will be a list of again dictionaries with type and URL in each one.
그 링크는 각각의 형식과 URL을 가진 사전의 목록이 되겠죠
And that URL is the full URL.
그 URL이 전체 URL이죠
So let me run this cell.
이 방을 운영하게 해줘요
And just to make sure that this is clear to you, let me just print link system prompt.
이게 명확한지 확인하기 위해 링크 시스템 프롬프트를 프린트할게요
So we now have a variable.
이제 변수가 생겼어요
And this is what that variable contains.
그 변수가 포함하는 게 이거죠
We print it out.
인쇄를 했어요
We'll get the carriage returns as well.
Get it, get it 마차도 다시 가져오죠
Let's have a look at this.
이걸 보시죠
Here it is.
여기 있네요
So this is exactly what we are going to instruct the LLM to do in our system prompt.
이게 바로 우리가 시스템 프롬프트에서 LLM에게 지시하려는 거죠
And now we're going to write a function get links user prompt.
이제 함수 get links 사용자 프롬프트를 쓸게요
And this is what it looks like.
이렇게 생긴 거예요
It will take a website object.
웹사이트 객체를 가져가요
And it's going to say here is a list of links on the website of blah.
여기 블라 웹사이트에 링크 목록이 있다고 할 거예요
Please decide which are relevant web links for a brochure about the company.
해당 회사 브로슈어에 실을 관련 링크를 골라 주세요
Respond with a full your URL do not include and a few things not to include and then list out the links
URL do 포함 안 함과 포함 안 함 몇 가지로 응답하세요 그런 다음 링크를
by one by one and return that.
하나씩 나열해 반환하세요
So this will make more sense if we look at an actual example.
실제 예제를 보면 더 이해가 잘 될 거예요
So let's call get Links user prompt and we'll pass in editor which is of course as before editor.
get Links 사용자 프롬프트라고 하죠 편집기로 넘기겠습니다 편집기 전처럼요
Is this one up here.
이 위에 있는 건가요?
It's going to be looking at these links.
이 링크들을 살펴볼 거예요
So let's see what this user prompt looks like.
이 사용자 프롬프트가 어떻게 생겼는지 보죠
And you should run this to and get a sense for it.
Get in을 실행해 보세요 감을 잡아야죠
This is what the user prompt would look like.
사용자 프롬프트는 이렇게 생겼을 거예요
It's sorry it says exactly what I just said.
제가 한 말을 그대로 전해서 죄송해요
Uh, it tells it that we're looking at this website, that fine website.
우리가 이 웹사이트를 보고 있다고 나와요
Uh, and then here are the links.
여기 링크가 있어요
Some might be relative and you should summarize and you should you should select the ones that are relevant.
어떤 것은 관련 있을 수 있으니 요약해서 관련 있는 것을 선택해야 하죠
Okay.
네
And now it's time to put all of this into a function which is going to call OpenAI.
이제 이 모든 걸 함수에 넣을 겁니다 OpenAI라고 하죠
And here it is get links URL.
get links URL이네요
So we'll create a new website object for that URL.
URL을 위한 새 웹사이트 객체를 생성할게요
And now we call this.
이제 이걸 이렇게 불러요
And I went through this quickly last time, and now it's time to spend a little bit more time on this.
지난번에 비트를 빠르게 훑어봤는데요 이번에는 여기에 시간을 좀 더 투자할 거예요
We call OpenAI chat, which is the main API for chats completions, which is the one that we will almost
OpenAI 채팅이라고 부르는데 채팅 완료를 위한 메인 API죠 거의 항상 사용하게 될
always use.
거예요
Is that the the API, which is the standard API where we're saying your task is to keep going, is to
API, 여러분의 작업이 계속되는 표준 API입니다 이 대화를
is to complete this conversation.
완료하는 거죠
And we create something on the completions API and it takes, as before, a model and messages the model
완료 API 상에서 뭔가를 생성하면 전처럼 모델과 전달할 모델에 메시지가 생겨요
It was a variable.
그게 변수였어요
We set GPT four mini right at the start.
GPT 4 미니를 출발선에 세팅했어요
Messages.
메시지예요
Hopefully this is already starting to be familiar to you.
벌써 익숙해지기 시작했길 바라요
The format that we use for messages is a list of dictionaries.
메시지 형식은 사전 목록이에요
It's a list of dictionaries where each dictionary, each dictionary has a key role with either system
각 사전, 각 사전은 시스템 또는 사용자와 관련된 핵심 역할과 관련된
or user, a key content with the associated system message or user message.
시스템 메시지나 사용자 메시지의 핵심 콘텐츠를 갖고 있죠
So.
그래서요?
System system message user.
시스템 메시지 사용자를 입력하세요
User message that is going in our messages list.
메시지 목록에 들어갈 사용자 메시지요
It's as simple as that.
아주 간단해요
I hope that this is completely connecting for you.
충분히 이해하셨길 바라요
There is one little extra detail, one tiny thing I'm throwing in there, and it's this here response
작은 추가 디테일이 하나 더 있어요 여기 응답 포맷이요
So you could tell OpenAI that we want it to provide a JSON object back in its response.
OpenAI에 JSON 개체를 다시 제공하라고 할 수 있어요
And we do that by passing this in type JSON object.
JSON 형식 객체를 통해 전달하죠
So that is something which is it's actually Claude doesn't doesn't have this way of requiring a JSON
그건 사실 클로드는 JSON 객체를 돌려받는 방법이
object back.
없어요
OpenAI does.
오픈아이는 알아요
But OpenAI mentions in their documentation that even when you use this, it's still important that you
OpenAI는 문서화에서 언급하길 이걸 사용할 때도 JSON 응답이 필요하다고
mention in your prompt that a JSON response is required.
반드시 언급해야 한다고 했어요
It will only work if you do mention that explicitly in your prompt also.
프롬프트에 명시적으로 언급해야 작동할 거예요
So we do that.
그렇게 하죠
What comes back is into this variable completion.
돌아오는 건 이 변수 완료죠
Actually, to keep this consistent with before, I'm going to change this to response because that's
사실 일관성을 유지하기 위해 이걸 응답으로 바꾸겠습니다 지난 번에
what we called it last time.
그렇게 불렀거든요
There we go.
됐어요
Uh, and, uh, what we then to to to actually get the final reply, we go response dot choices zero.
최종 답변을 얻기 위해서는 응답 .선택을 선택하세요. get
So what's this about?
무슨 일이죠?
Well, as it happens we can actually in the API request ask to have multiple variations if we want,
실제로 API 요청에서 여러 변형을 요청할 수 있어요 여러 가지 가능한
if we wanted it to generate several possible variations of the response.
변형을 생성하길 원하는 경우에요
And we haven't done that.
우린 그러지 않았죠
So we're only going to get back one.
Get in get은 하나네요
Uh, and so those variations come back in the form of these choices.
그런 변형이 이런 선택 형태로 나타난 거죠
But we've only got one.
하지만 하나밖에 없어요
So choices zero is getting us the one and the only choice of the response back.
0번 선택은 유일한 응답을 받게 해주죠
So that's why you'll always see response dot choices zero dot message dot content is just simply drilling
그래서 항상 응답이 .선택 .0,Message.content인 거죠 텍스트 메시지가 되돌아오는
down to what is actually the text message back.
것으로 드릴다운하는 거예요
So basically you get very familiar with these two two things because it's the same in many, many times
기본적으로 이 두 가지에 아주 익숙해지게 됩니다 API 호출은 많은 경우에
that we call the API.
같거든요
We'll be doing the same thing OpenAI dot chat, dot completions, dot create and then with what comes
OpenAI.챗, .완성, .생성 그리고 응답 .선택,
back it's response dot choices, zero Message content.
0 메시지 콘텐츠도 똑같이 할 거예요
You will get to the point when you'll be reciting it in your sleep.
Get it, get it, get it get it, get it it, it 자면서도 외울 수 있는 수준까지 가셔야 해요
And then with what comes back, we're going to use the Json.load string function to then bring that
그런 다음 돌아온 것으로 Json을 사용하죠 문자열 함수를 불러와 JSON으로
back as JSON.
불러오죠
Let's run that.
실행해 보죠
Okay.
네
So we're going to take the plunge.
그래서 과감하게 도전했죠
We're going to call that that function and pass in the website anthropic comm.
그걸 함수라고 부르고 웹사이트 anthropiccom에 넘길 거예요
So what are we expecting it to do.
그럼 어떻게 되는 거죠?
We're expecting it to collect all of the links on that page and then call uh call GPT four mini and
해당 페이지의 모든 링크를 수집한 다음 GPT for 미니에 호출해 관련 있다고
say please select from this some links which you think are relevant and respond with them.
생각되는 링크를 선택해 응답하라고 하는 거죠
So let's see what we get.
get get을 해 보죠
Here we go.
시작할게요
It's going off now to OpenAI.
오픈아이로 출발하네요
Well it's first it had to collect the anthropic page and back it comes.
인류 문명의 페이지를 수집해서 돌려줘야 해요
And this is what we get type about page.
이게 Get in get page죠
And there's a link to the about page a careers page, a team page, research enterprise pricing, API
링크가 있어요 경력 페이지, 팀 페이지 리서치 엔터프라이즈 가격, API 그리고
and news.
뉴스요
How about that?
어때요?
This is all actually great information that we would want on a brochure, and no doubt there are a ton
모두 브로슈어에 실어야 할 훌륭한 정보예요 포함되지 않은 링크가
of links that it hasn't included.
엄청나게 많죠
Let's convince ourselves of that.
우리 스스로를 설득해 보죠
We can say, uh, anthropic is website and just pass this in.
앤스로픽 이즈 웹사이트라고 하고 전달할 수 있어요
And do anthropic dot links and we'll see what are all of the links that were on that page here?
종족유사 닷 링크라고 입력하면∙∙∙ 이 페이지에 링크가 다 뭐죠?
They all are.
전부 다 그래요
There's a ton of them like supported countries and lots of others.
지원하는 나라가 정말 많네요
You'll also see that there are many of them that are not fully, uh, the full URL, including the the
또한 많은 경우 완전한 URL이 아닌 것도 보이실 겁니다 호스트 이름을 포함해서요
And so you'll see that and that our call to GPT four mini has very well selected a subset of these fully
GPT for 미니에 대한 호출이 정규화된 하위 집합을 잘 선택해 무엇인지 설명하는
qualified them and explained what they are.
걸 보실 수 있어요
I'd say that's a great result.
좋은 결과라고 생각해요
That was pretty easy to it's just step one of the two steps that we have to go through to build our
아주 쉬웠어요 회사 브로슈어를 만들 때 거쳐야 하는 두 단계 중
company brochure.
하나였죠
And I will see you in the next video for step two.
그럼 다음 2단계 영상에서 만나요